#### Darrell Abrau

DarrellAbrau@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

Software developer with 5 years of full-stack web development experience. Looking for opportunities to grow as a front-end developer. Passionate about learning new technologies and contributing to great products.

**SKILLS:** React, Redux, Webpack, D3, Plotly, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Flask, Postgres, Git, Python, Docker, Linux, Ruby, Scala

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Invitae

Software Engineer

December 2018 - current

- Developed new features for a web application to support laboratory production workflows from concept to deployment.
- Created custom web embedded data visualizations with D3 and Plotly.
- Contributed to and maintained shared front-end components.
- Integrated internal API's into the web application by collaborating with other teams.
- Mentored junior developers.

# **UCSF / Immunoprofiler**

Data Scientist

February 2017 - December 2018

- Contributed to the UI and API of a web application for browsing laboratory data.
- Developed web embedded data visualizations for reporting.
- Re-tooled the front-end code base to use ES2015, Babel, ESlint and Jest.
- Generated data visualizations for scientific research papers and data exploration.
- Analyzed data in collaboration with researchers to answer scientific questions.

# **Avention**

Software Engineer

January 2015 - June 2016

- Contributed to the development and documentation of a new customer facing RESTful API.
- Designed and developed the user notification system for a single page application.
- Developed an in-house tool for synchronizing user data from a legacy system.
- Investigated and resolved back-end and front-end bugs.

### Life Technologies

Scientist 1 September 2012 - July 2014

Hospira

Chemistry Analyst

February 2011 - September 2012

# **EDUCATION**

**MakerSquare** Student Software Developer August 2014 - November 2014

**The University of Texas at Austin** B.S. in Biochemistry

December 2010